## NAVEEN VINTA

## Washington D.C Metro

(312) 622-2648 linkedin.com/in/nvinta naveen.vinta@icloud.com

## TRANSFORMATIVE TECHNOLOGY LEADER

#### DRIVING STRATEGIC DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION WITH INCLUSIVITY

As an IT leader with experience in Cybersecurity, Solution Architecture, and Cloud Computing and a US Army veteran, I am pursuing an Executive MBA to further develop my business acumen and pivot to operator roles in private equity. Led high-performing teams managing budgets of \$50M+; I excel at delivering exceptional results and maximizing impact for the mission and team. My adaptable leadership style ensures strategic alignment with organizational goals, making me well-suited to drive business transformation and create value for private equity firms.

- Technical Strategy
- Cybersecurity Policy
- Program Management

- Client Relations
- Team Building and Mentoring
- Managed 50M + P&L

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# THE ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY, Washington, D.C Information Management Officer

2023-Present

- Advised Senior Information Officer (SIO) and high-level executives, providing guidance on technology innovation and implementing digital transformation initiatives within the Office of Water (OW).
- Liaised between IT professionals and technical program experts, as a technology SME.
- Led strategic initiatives to improve IT operations and programs, resulting in a 30% increase in operational efficiency and 15% reduction in costs.
- Managed risks to IT system and data by identifying, assessing, and mitigating potential risks, resulting in appropriate risk management and reduced overall risk.
- Monitor emerging trends and recommend improvements to increase efficiency and reduce release time by up to 50%.

CGI, Fairfax, VA 2020-2023

## **Director Consulting Services**

- Executed a cloud-first strategy, resulting in revenue increase of 25% and 20% improvement in P&L.
- Managed program with three task orders totaling \$50M, overseeing a team of 30 resources and delivering 95% of projects on-time and under budget.
- Enhanced client relations by delivering actionable insights and recommendations for digital transformation, resulting in 30% increase in customer satisfaction.
- Expanded portfolio by identifying opportunities and leveraging capabilities, resulting in a 15% increase in year-over-year growth.
- Improved recruitment, retention, and member satisfaction, providing coaching and mentorship resulting in a 40% increase in internal promotions.
- Led the effort to successfully win the recompete of a cybersecurity contract with a 40% increased total contract value.

## U.S DEPARTMENT OF STATE, Washington, D.C.

2016-2020

## **Information System Security Officer & Project Manager**

- Led Certification and Accreditation of FISMA High-Value Asset, achieving compliance with federal regulations and standards.
- Reviewed and evaluated customer responsibility matrix for FedRamp-certified Cloud Service Providers (SalesForce, ServiceNow, Microsoft Azure, Oracle Fusion Cloud), improving compliance and security.

- Managed a team of 20 resources modernizing applications into Service Oriented Architecture improving interoperability and ease of maintenance.
- Improved customer service for HR IT functions, resulting in increased satisfaction and streamlined processes.

## U.S DEPARTMENT OF LABOR, Washington, D.C.

2015-2016

## IT Specialist

- Oversaw contractor work as IT Specialist for Office of Information Systems and Technology (OIST) in Employment and Training Administration, ensuring successful project delivery.
- Procured department-wide IDaaS solution, improving security and streamlining access management across the organization.

## BANKERS LIFE, Chicago, IL

2013-2015

## Sr. Lead Application Developer

- Designed Spring MVC portal application with single sign-on for 6,000 agents, 400 corporate users, and 50 support technicians, enabling access to compensation statements, training, policies, history, and applications.
- Created Use Case, sequence, activity, state, architecture, and deployment diagrams, conducting fit-gap analysis to address stakeholder requirements.
- Presented to senior leadership on the application, and provided training to end users.

#### US ARMY, Ft. Bliss, TX

2010-2013

#### **Specialist**

M1A1 Abrams Tank Mechanic

## FORD MOTOR COMPANY, Dearborn, MI

2007-2010

## Sr. Developer

- Designed new online BOM process to assist Material Departments with early BOM process for future vehicle programs, replacing existing bulky process.
- Contributed to Ford's Blue Oval Certification, streamlining personnel certification process for dealer employees resulting in a 15% increased year-over-year sales.
- Led the effort to integrate IT modules with TATA resulting from an acquisition.

## NORTH DAKOTA STATE UNIVERSITY, Fargo, ND

2005-2007

#### **Research Assistance**

Worked as a research assistant in the Electrical and Computer Engineering.

- Designed sensor network with RFID capability and GPS for food transportation, used by multiple departments throughout campus.
- Developed Java components to interpret data in engineering units from three devices and export results to MySQL.
- Created GUI to monitor network trace and communication between nodes.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Virginia Darden School of Business, Rosslyn, VA

**Executive MBA Candidate** April, 2024

## George Mason University, Fairfax, VA

Master of Science in Technology Management

May, 2020

#### North Dakota State University, Fargo, ND

Master of Software Engineering

August, 2017